（ナレーション）帝光(ていこう)中学校
バスケットボール部
The Teiko Middle School basketball club.
An incredibly strong team with over one hundred members and three consecutive championship wins.
部員数は100を超え
全中三連覇を誇る 超強豪校
その輝かしい歴史の中でも
特に“最強”と呼ばれ—
Even within that brilliant history,
a group of five prodigies known as the
"Generation of Miracles" stood above the rest.
無敗を誇った10年に１人の天才が
５人同時にいた世代は—
“キセキの世代”と言われている
However, there was a strange rumor concerning the Generation of Miracles.
が “キセキの世代”には
奇妙なうわさがあった
Despite being relatively unknown
誰も知らない 試合記録もない
and lacking a game record,
there was one more member
recognized by the five prodigies.
にもかかわらず—
天才５人が 一目置いていた
選手がもう１人
幻のシックスマンがいた と
A phantom sixth man.
Let's fly now.
Author        Tadatoshi Fujimaki
Published in Shounen Jump
Let's try now.
Let's
fly
now.
Get
my
stage!
Let's
try
now.
Next
my
stage!
Let's
fly
now.
Translation Check   AMS
Get
my
stage!
Let's
fly
now.
Now!
Running into the middle of that exciting stage...
mu
ne
o
do
ru
su
tee
ji
e
ka
ke
a
ga
ru
do
ma
nna
ka
de
K-Timing      Eternal Blizzard
Editing      AMS
Continually breakthrough your limits.
ka
gi
ri
na
ku
ri
n
ka
i
te
n
to
ppa
mi
se
te
yo
Timing       ninjacloud
We have dreams, we're fond of legends, everybody in the ring.
yu
me
ta
shi
na
mu
re
je
n
do
every
body
wa
no
na
ka
de
Don't hesitate, into the future, JUMP!
ma
yo
i
na
ku
mi
ra
i
e
no
JUMP
Typesetting      KmE, zegond
They all say they haven't fallen after they have.
o
chi
bu
re
te
na
i
to
o
chi
bu
re
te
ka
ra
i
u
ya
tsu
ba
kka
It's scary aiming at coming back from the dead but
ki
shi
ka
i
se
ne
ra
u
mi
chi
no
ri
ko
wa
ku
na
wa
i
ga
QC      muyg, sangofe,
ninjacloud
if the road is still blocked
ko
e
te
ku
ka
be
na
no
ni
tsu
u
ka
te
n
na
no
ni
Karaokes      KmE
after I've crossed all the barriers,
fu
sa
i
de
ru
na
ra
I need to realize I'm not alone.
hi
to
ri
ja
na
i
ji
ka
ku
o
Slam it!
t
o
d
k
e
We have to set the rim on fire!
w
e
h
a
v
e
t
o
m
a
k
e
a
R
I
M
F
I
R
E
Let's combine our power and our minds.
a
w
s
e
r
o
p
w
e
r
n
o
a
k
n
o
m
i
n
d
Encoding      Your Mom
We don't need any excuses.
i
w
a
k
e
i
r
a
n
z
o
Gotta dream, exceed your limits, and war.
G
o
t
a
d
r
e
a
m
g
e
n
k
a
i
t
o
w
a
r
I need to face up to my common sense,
ta
chi
ha
da
ka
ru
no
wa
ri
ka
i
shi
su
gi
ta
Kuroko's
I
(
)
I
(
)
Basketball
joushiki to
which I know all too well,
kodoku no maibotsu
and bury my loneliness.
RIM
FIRE!!
Come visit us at www.saizen-fansubs.com
These guys...
（火神(かがみ)）こいつら…
Their offense and defense is all one-on-one.
オフェンスもディフェンスも
とにかく１対１
自分でボールを取りに行って
自分で決める…
You get the ball yourself and score yourself.
They keep coming at us with individual skill!
個人技で ひたすら
ガンガンきやがる！
When you heard Aomine would be late,
（今吉(いまよし)）おおかた
青峰(あおみね)が遅れるて聞いて—
できるだけ点差つけようと
思てたんちゃう？
I bet you thought you could open
up a big lead before he showed up.
We're probably stronger than you.
君らよりは強いで たぶん
（火神）ふんっ 甘(あめ)えよ！
You're naive!
I know. I thought you might try that.
（さつき）知ってますよー
そう来ると思ってたから
We must have been scouted by that girl.
（リコ）研究されてるわね
恐らくあの子に
（桜井(さくらい)）あ！
Forget one-on-ones.
（日向(ひゅうが)）１対１の勝負はともかく…
ふっ！
試合にまで 負ける気はねーぞ
I don't plan on losing this game.
Tell your captain, you apologetic mushroom.
主将にもそう言っとけ 謝りキノコ
（黒子(くろこ)）うっ！
（リコ）あっ！ ウソ！
You're kidding!
The truth is, I don't want to send out an injured player,
（リコ）本当は 万全でない選手を
出すなんて やりたくないけど—
but we can't win without you.
火神君がいないと勝てないわ
You're the coach.
試合中ぐらいは…
You've got to at least come prepared for games.
カントクなんだから
ドーンと構えてくんねーと…
（リコ）生意気 言ってくれるわね
バカガミが！
You're a brat, you idiot.
Go get them!
（リコ）行ってこい！
Yeah!
ウッス！
That's it, show some spirit
（青峰）そうそう
張り切ってくれよ
so you can entertain me a little.
（青峰）少しでも オレを
楽しませられるようにさ
テメェ 青峰！
You bastard!
Aomine!
Touou
Seirin
（今吉）やっと来たか まったく…
You're finally here?
早よ 準備して 出てくれや！
Hurry up and get ready so you can play!
（青峰）えー
つか 勝ってんじゃん
What? But you're winning.
No, you have to play.
（原澤(はらさわ)）ダメです 出なさい
（火神）く…
（青峰）はあ〜 ま いーけど
Fine.
Well, then...
（青峰）じゃあ…
（さつき）ああっ
やろーか
Let's go.
Episode 17
You're All Ridiculous
Touou
Seirin
Touou Academy, member change!
（オフィシャル）
桐皇(とうおう)学園 メンバーチェンジです
（日向）こいつが 青峰大輝(だいき)…
This is Aomine Daiki.
（伊月）カントクみたいな
特別な目がなくても—
Even normal basketball players like us can tell he's different,
普通のバスケ部員の
オレたちでも分かる
even without the coach's special eyes.
（火神）アメリカでも
ここまでのは 会ったことねえ
I never even met anyone this good in America.
黒子のいた中学 最強のレギュラー
天才５人の１人—
Kuroko's middle school's strongest regular.
One of the five prodigies...
The ace of the Generation of Miracles!
“キセキの世代”のエース
（リコ）しかも点差つけるどころか
10点ビハインド
Not only did we fail to get ahead, but we're ten points behind.
He got here at the worst possible time.
最悪のタイミングで
来てくれたわね
よう テツ 久しぶりだな
Hey, Tetsu. It's good to see you again.
どんな顔するかと思えば…
I was wondering what face you'd make.
いーじゃん
やる気 満々ってツラだな
I like it. You look ready to go.
Yes. I promised Momoi.
（黒子）はい
桃井(ももい)さんと約束しましたから
ハハッ 言いたいことは
大体 分かるけどな
I more or less understand what you want to say,
それはプレーで示すことだろ？
まあ どっちにしろ—
but you'll have to show me that with your play.
Well, either way...
Say it once you've beaten me.
勝ってから言えよ
はい
All right.
できるもんならな
If you can do it.
やってやらあ！
すぐに見せてやる！
Bring it on! We'll show you right away!
What's this?
（大坪(おおつぼ)）これは？
Hey, their balance is off.
（女性）ねえねえ なんか
バランス悪いっていうか—
やけに人数 寄ってない？
Don't they have too many guys on one side?
（男性）いや 違うよ
ありゃ 寄せてんだよ
No, they're doing it on purpose.
Isolation.
（黄瀬(きせ)）アイソレーション
In order to allow special players to move freely,
（緑間(みどりま)）特定のプレーヤーが
スペースを使いやすいように—
残りの選手が片側に寄る
the remaining players gather on one side.
There are several reasons to do this,
（緑間）使うときの理由は
いくつかあるが—
but in this situation, it's exactly what it looks like.
この場合は 見たままなのだよ
つまり—
In other words,
it's a one-on-one between both teams' aces.
両チーム
エースのワンオンワンだ
（伊月）速い！ あっさり
あの火神をチギるのかよ！？
He's fast!
He can get by Kagami that easily?
Amazing!
（日向）すげえ！
（火神）えいっ！
（青峰）あん！？ あのロールの
一瞬で追いついたのかよ？
He caught up in the second it took to spin?
He stopped him!
止めた！
All right, Kagami!
（小金井(こがねい)）よっしゃあ 火神！
So high!
高い！
How'd he jump so high from that position?
（黄瀬）つか あの体勢で
あそこまで！？
ん… とおっ
Now! Fast break!
今だ 速攻！！
（福田(ふくだ)･河原(かわはら)）ああ！ 戻り 早っ！
They're quick to get back!
And they know all the upperclassmen's
movements from their research!
（降旗(ふりはた)）しかも 先輩たちの動きは
研究されて 読まれてるのに！
You can take your slow fast break and shove it!
（若松(わかまつ)）んなトロい速攻
おととい来やがれ！ ボケコラ！！
What is that?
なっ！？ あれは！？
The pass only Kagami can catch!
（降旗）火神しか取れない—
イグナイトパス！！
The Ignite Pass!
ぬあーっ！！
（青峰）ええい！
（火神）なっ！？
He was off-balance and slow to get back.
（日向）バランス崩して
戻り遅れてたのに！
（リコ）速い！
He's so fast!
Oh? It's over?
あれ？ 終わり？
ああ アップがてら さくっと１本
決めるつもりだったのに
I was going to score one as a quick warm-up.
チッ なんだよそれ
ったく！
What is this? Damn...
Pretty good though.
いいじゃねーか オイ！
At ten points behind, I thought you guys must suck,
10点差つけられて
どんだけひどいかと思えば—
but you're not bad, are you?
なかなかマシじゃねーの？
Amazing. That's Aomine...
（観客１）すげえ あれが青峰？
Don't you think he's ridiculously fast?
（観客２）
めちゃくちゃ速くね！？
A normal person can barely keep up.
素人目にも ハンパねーよ！
Aominecchi...
（黄瀬）青峰っち…
まったく 気に食わんヤツなのだよ
He's completely unbearable.
ノロすぎる
まるで やる気が なかったのだよ
He's slow. It's like he has no desire to play.
Aomine, you bastard, play as hard as you can!
（若松）青峰テメー
ちゃんと本気でやれよ！
You let that guy block you.
あっさり
ブロックとか されやがって
あ？ ハハッ
本気とかないわ ダルいし
What?
I can't play that hard. I'm tired.
You bastard!
テメー！
But...
けどまあ—
I might actually try in the second half.
後半は 出すかも 本気
（アナウンス）
第２クオーター終了です
The second quarter is over.
なお第３クオーターは—
The third quarter will begin after a ten minute break.
インターバル 10分後の開始です
Touou Academy
Dressing Room
Ryo, did you bring them?
Touou Academy
Dressing Room
（青峰）良(りょう) 例のモン
ちゃんと持ってきたんだろうな？
Touou Academy
Dressing Room
Y-Yes...
（桜井）あ… はいっ
Thanks.
（青峰）おう
Man, these are good.
ああ うめ！
青峰テメー！
何食ってん… つか—
Aomine, what are you eating?!
You haven't played enough to need to replenish yourself!
補給するほど出てねーだろ
コラ！
And, Sakurai, don't make him food!
桜井も ほいほい
作ってんじゃねーよ
What are you, his manager?
マネージャーか！？
（桜井）す… すいません ああ！
S-Sorry...
I'm way more tired!
（若松）オレのほうが
よっぽど疲れてるわ！
ああ… わ… 若松さん！
Um, Wakamatsu...
（今吉）オレにもくれ
Give me some.
Wow, these are delicious!
ああ うめー！
もう ねーぞ バーカ！
There's none left, you idiot!
（青峰）いんねーし もう
I don't want any more.
（若松）んだと コラ！？
What did you say?!
Don't eat all of them.
てか 全部食うなや！
It's okay. I made some too.
（さつき）大丈夫ですよ
私も作ってきましたから
Oh, thanks.
ああ スマンの
桜井 もう ないんか？
Sakurai, do you have any more?
Sorry, I'm all out.
すいません もう…
Yeah, Satsuki's cooking is terrible.
（青峰）ああ さつきは
ひでーよ 料理
（今吉）ていうか
料理以前のレベルやろ コレは！？
Isn't this a level below cooking?!
Good work in the first half!
前半お疲れ様！
後半の逆転に向けて これ
エネルギー補給よ！
I made you these so we can make our comeback in the second!
They'll replenish your energy!
Slice them!
切ってって！ 切ってって
言ってるじゃん いつも！
We're always telling you to slice them!
ちゃんと洗ったから
皮ごといけると…
I washed them, so you can eat the skin.
あと いっぱい食べられるし！
And you'll be able to eat lots!
Mitobe, do you have any?
水戸部(みとべ)！ ある？
Mitobe, I'm so glad you're on our team.
水戸部いて よかったあ
アーハッハッハ
Kuroko, don't you want any?
黒子 いんねーのか？
No, I'm good.
すみません ボクはいいです
Kuroko, you played the whole first half, so I'm taking you out for a bit.
黒子君 君は前半
出ずっぱりだったから—
一度 引っ込んでもらうけど
栄養補給は しなきゃダメよ
You have to replenish your nutrients.
（黒子）あの—
Um, could you let me keep play the entire second half too?
後半も このまま
出してもらえませんか？
What?
Come on, it's too early to relax.
（原澤）ほらほら
なごむのは まだ早いですよ
Let's talk about the second half.
後半の話をしましょう
（青峰）ああ オレ パス
I'll pass.
（若松）青峰テメー！ 待てよ！
Aomine, you bastard! Wait!
後半はオレが全部決める…
で いーじゃん
I'll make all my shots in the second half.
That should do it, right?
（若松）な！？ テメー コラ！
You bastard!
As long as you understand.
分かっていればいいです
ちゃんと アップしてきなさい
Make sure you warm-up.
Okay.
へーい
Aomine!
（さつき）青峰君！
（若松）監督！
Coach!
（今吉）若松
もう 毎度 あんまりゴネんなや
Wakamatsu, don't make such a big deal every time.
（若松）けどあんな態度…
調子こきすぎでしょ！？
But that attitude...
Don't you think he's too arrogant?
Who cares if he is?
別にええんちゃう？ こいても
テレビのインタビューとかで
感じたことあらへんか？
Haven't you ever felt it in a TV interview?
一流選手で こいてるヤツなんて
ザラやんけ
There's plenty of arrogant superstars.
Put negatively, it's arrogance, insolence.
悪く言えば傲慢 不遜
けどよく言えば
勝ち続けてきたゆえの圧倒的自信や
But put positively,
it's their complete confidence that has been made from their successive victories.
Don't get the wrong idea.
ああ 勘違いすんなや
I don't particularly like or dislike Aomine.
ワシは別に 青峰のこと
好きでも 嫌いでもないで
As long as he scores, I don't care what his personality is like.
点さえ取れば
人格なんて どーでもええ
As long as we win, he's right.
勝ってる限り あいつが正義や
No matter what kind of guy Aomine is,
青峰が どんな人間でも
試合に出れば 文句はないわ
I have no complaints as long as he plays.
We're most likely to win if he does.
それが一番
勝率が高いからな
（桜井）いつも思う
I've always thought
that our team is united by our selfishness.
このチームは 打算でつながってる
We abandon trust, and each man is out for himself.
信頼とは無縁で
根っこはバラバラだ
But for some reason,
けど なんでだろ？
負ける気がしない
I don't feel like we'll lose.
I've had enough! I can't believe you were late!
ホントにもう 遅刻なんて
信じられない どういうつもり！？
What do you think you're doing?
We're up against Tetsu's team!
相手は テツ君のいるチームよ
後半からは ちゃんと…
In the second half, you'd better—
Shut up. I know.
（青峰）うっせーな 分かってるよ
これでも反省してんだぜ
I feel bad about what I did.
（青峰）ちょっと読み違ったからな
I misread them a little.
I should have shown up sooner.
もっと早く来ても よかったわ
確かに 青峰いて
黒子抜きは きちーけど—
Aomine will be tough without Kuroko.
Can we even manage it?
てか いけんのかよ？
（リコ）後半 連続はね…
Two consecutive halves...
１試合フルには—
Your misdirection won't work for a whole game, right?
ミスディレクションは
続かないんだろ？
I don't think we should do it.
（伊月）オレは反対だな
イーグルアイで 見てたけど
もう ずいぶん 効果が落ちてる
I've been watching with my eagle eye,
but your effectiveness has already dropped off quite a bit.
You should sit out for a while.
一度 下がるべきだ
できます いえ やります
I can do it.
No, I will do it.
どうしても
青峰君に勝ちたいんです
I will do anything to beat Aomine.
Kuroko's
I
Basketball
I will do anything to beat Aomine.
（黒子）どうしても
青峰君に勝ちたいんです
I appreciate your enthusiasm, but...
意気込みは 買うけどよ
（リコ）前半も 黒子君を
外すゆとりは なかった
We couldn't afford to bench Kuroko in the first half.
It'll only be harder with Aomine.
青峰君が入れば
当然 さらにキツくなる
かといって 出し続ければ
最後までもたない
But if we make him keep playing, he won't last until the end.
What should we do?
どうする！？
カントク さっきの ください
Coach, could I get those?
What?
（火神）黒子
Kuroko...
Just eat those on the bench, you idiot.
いーから 食って引っ込めよ バカ！
バスケは １人で
やるもんじゃねーって—
You're the one who said you can't play basketball by yourself!
言ったのは オマエだろ！
Leave it to us!
任せとけ
（リコ）どっちを選んでも
リスクばかりで 答えはない
Both choices are risky and I can't reach an answer.
If that's the case, I'll have to rely on our ace's enthusiasm.
だったら ウチのエースの
気合いを買うか！
よし！
Okay!
後半 黒子君は 一度下げるわ
We'll take Kuroko out for a little bit during the second half.
Our battle will begin in the fourth quarter!
第４クオーターに勝負よ！
とは言え 取り返しが
つかなくなったら 意味がない
But it's meaningless if we pass the point of no return.
Be ready to play any time in case we get close.
いつでも出られる準備 しててね
Have some lemons.
（リコ）レモンでも食べて
Their inside is especially strong.
向こうは インサイドが 特に強いわ
We'll put in Tsuchida during the third quarter.
第３クオーターは 土田君 入って
You and Mitobe will guard the rim!
水戸部君と２人で
ゴール下 お願い！
（リコ）日向君と伊月君は
前半と同じ
Hyuga and Izuki, keep doing what you did in the first half.
Keep marks on that mushroom, No. 9...
９番のキノコと…
（桜井）すいません！
Sorry!
and that glasses-wearing No. 4.
（リコ）４番のメガネをマーク
一番の問題は 青峰君だけど—
The biggest problem is Aomine,
but there's only one guy who can handle him.
対抗できるのは
もちろん １人しかいないわ
火神君 任せたわよ！
Kagami, we're counting on you!
ウスッ！
Got it!
行くぞ 誠凛(せいりん)！ ファイ！！
Let's go, Seirin!
Seirin High
.....Dressing Room
Fight!
Yeah!
Kagami...
（黒子）火神君
（火神）なんだよ？
What?
Have you calmed down a little?
ちょっとは頭 冷えたかよ？
Yes. More importantly...
はい それより
ボクは開花してからの青峰君の底を
見たことがありません
I have not seen Aomine's limits since he bloomed.
しかも 黄瀬君や緑間君 同様
進化しているはずです
Not only that, but just like Kise and Midorima,
he has probably grown.
Going forward, he is an unknown entity.
だから この先の彼は 未知数です
Be careful.
気をつけてください
ハッ 望むところだよ
I couldn't ask for more.
He's here.
来たか
とっとと やろーぜ
Let's do this already.
His body is properly warmed up.
（日向）体 キッチリ
あったまってる
完全にマジモード！
He's completely serious now.
Hey, did you finish warming up?
よう アップは済んだのかよ？
Keep fighting until the end.
だから 最後まで あらがえよ
できればな
If you have it in you.
The third quarter will now begin!
（アナウンス）これより
第３クオーターを開始します
Kuroko's on the bench.
（高尾(たかお)）黒子 ベンチっスね
大丈夫かよ？
Are they going to be okay?
（緑間）やむをえん… が—
It can't be helped,
but they couldn't afford to sub Kuroko out in the first half even without Aomine.
前半 青峰抜きでも
黒子を代えられなかったのに—
I don't believe they can endure this.
とても しのげるとは
思えないのだよ
そうっスね
You're right.
（黄瀬）確かに 青峰っち相手に
黒子っち抜きは 厳しすぎる
Playing against Aominecchi without Kurokocchi is too hard.
けどオレは
あの成長スピードを考えると—
But when I consider the rate of his growth,
I get the feeling something's going to happen.
何か起きそうな気がするんス
He can do it.
あいつなら！
（観客１）うーっ！
（観客２）開始早々 青峰か！
Aomine's playing already.
It'll be all him, not just now, but for the entire second half.
（リコ）早々どころか 後半は まず
間違いなく ほとんど彼でしょうね
The ace of the Generation of Miracles and a super scorer...
“キセキの世代”エースにして
スーパー スコアラー
（伊月）何もできず
黒子を すぐ出すようなら—
If we're forced to put in Kuroko right away,
he'll run out of gas and the fourth quarter will only get worse.
ガス欠で
第４クオーターはジリ貧だ
We can't do anything against him.
（日向）オレらじゃまず
手も足も出ねえ
頼むぜ 火神！
It's up to you, Kagami!
You're fired up.
（青峰）気合い
イイ感じ じゃねーの
Does this mean it won't be like that time in the park?
前 公園でやったときとは
違うってことか？
けどまあ… ムダだぜ！
Well, either way...
It's pointless.
（伊月）まただ！
あの火神が ついていけない！？
Again! Kagami can't keep up!
（火神）フェイクに
かかったわけじゃねーのに—
He didn't fake me out, but I still can't keep up!
なんつーキレだ！
He's unbelievably fast!
The help is fast!
ヘルプ早い！
And there's two of them!
しかも２人だ！
A fadeaway?
（伊月）フェイダウェイ！？
あのスピードから
急停止して 後ろに跳ぶか！？
How can anyone make such a quick stop at that speed and jump backwards?
We can't even keep up with quick help.
（日向）早いヘルプも追いつかねえ
スピードのケタが違う！
He's in a different class!
（緑間）運動において
速さとは 最高速だけではない
When it comes to movement,
speed is not all about maximum speed.
ゼロからマックスへの加速力と—
Your acceleration from zero to max,
and your deceleration from max to zero.
マックスからゼロへの減速力
アジリティ… すなわち 敏しょう性
Agility, how quick you are on your feet.
青峰のそれは“キセキの世代”の
中でも ズバ抜けている
Even among the Generation of Miracles, Aomine transcends the rest of us.
（火神）ええいっ！ くそっ！
Damn it!
ダメか！？
さっきより 一段と速(はえ)え！
I can't keep up. He's even faster than before.
This guy...
（青峰）こいつ！
Touou
Seirin
ケッ あんくらいオレにだって
Even I could do that.
はっ アカン！
No!
（さつき）速攻！？
A fast break!
Throw it down, Kagami!
（降旗）ぶちこめー！ 火神！
Take this!
（火神）くらえっ！
だあーっ！！
No, you don't.
（青峰）させねーよ
（火神）どんなに速く攻めても
こいつは振り切れない！
No matter how fast I run,
I can't break free of this guy!
You think I'd let you score that easily?
なーに やすやすと
速攻とった気で いんだよ？
（青峰）こいつ マジかよ？
Is this guy for real?
He just jumped from the free throw line.
今の踏み切り位置…
フリースローラインじゃねーか
Don't tell me he was trying to dunk from there.
あそこからダンクでも—
決めるつもりだったんじゃ
ねえだろーな？
Come on now.
Damn it, that was close.
ああ くそっ 惜しいっ
けどよ 思ったより全然やれてるぜ
この調子なら…
But we're doing better than I expected!
At this rate, we could...
（青峰）ハッ やめだ
Enough.
Honest basketball just isn't for me.
やっぱ性に合わねーわ
生真面目なバスケは
He seems different.
（火神）今までと雰囲気が違う
でも こいつの速さとリズムは
分かってきた
But I'm starting to get a feel for his speed and rhythm.
I'll stop him this time!
次は止める！
（日向）なんだこの動き
読めない！ 変則！？
What are these movements?
I can't read them. Is this some kind of anomaly?
（火神）違う！ 型にはまらない
トリッキーな動き…
No! They're unconventional tricky movements.
I've seen this plenty of times in America.
アメリカでずっと見てきた—
It's street ball!
ストリートのバスケだ！
No you don't!
させっかあ！！
Three guys?
３人！？
（リコ）ゴールの裏！
（小金井）止めた！
He's behind the basket!
We stopped him!
Amazing!
（観客１）すごい！
He made a shot from behind the basket!
（観客２）あの位置から
ゴールを決めた！
（リコ）何よそれ…！？
なんてデタラメ！
What was that?
That's ridiculous!
This guy's basketball is more than aggressive.
（日向）強引 通り越して
メチャクチャだ こいつのバスケは
The way this guy plays...
It doesn't make any sense!
セオリーが まったく通じない！
The Generation of Miracles is full of ridiculous guys.
つくづく“キセキの世代”ってのは
ふざけたヤツばっかりだ
Honnouteki naru situation
An instinctive situation,
tatakau imi o sagasu kono imitation
searching for a reason to fight this imitation.
Kurayami kara koboreru raito
Use the light that seeps from the darkness,
torawareta yourself kowase
and break free from your imprisonment.
Jiyuu ukeirete wa mogaite kuratte fuantei
Accept your freedom and struggle through your insecurities.
Kodou ga boku o tsukiage spy kidottenda
The pulsation throws me for a loop and I begin to spy.
Bring back the Catalyst "a simple way to best"
Bring back the Catalyst "a simple way to best."
And Rhythm like this never ends
And Rhythm like this never ends.
Sometimes your voice reached to me
Sometimes your voice reached to me,
Because I don't want to face the fate
because I dont want to face the fate.
Tobi tachitaku naru tte?
You say you wanna jump back up?
Katarurizumu oboete ndarou
You remember the catal rhythm, don't you?
Mune ni hibiku akirame no kako e
To the past resounding resignation in your chest,
Sabita sukoaboodo mitai ni
like a rusty scoreboard,
kimi mo koko de furuete ndarou?
you're shaking, aren't you?
Toriaezu wa mayoi no nai mirai e
For now, confidently head into the future.
Zanzou demo ii nda
Even if it's just a fragment of yourself.
Future aspect
Next Episode
（青峰）火神だけじゃ
もの足りねえ 出てこいよ テツ
Kagami by himself isn't enough.
Come on out, Tetsu.
（黒子）１人で勝てるとは
思ってません
I don't believe I can win alone.
火神君と一緒に
青峰君を倒します！
I will beat you together with Kagami.
Touou
Seirin
（青峰）見せてみろよ
新しい光と影の底力をよ！
Show me the true strength of the new light and shadow.
Episode 18
No!!